[theme song playing]
[roars]
Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters.
DEPARTURE x AND x FRIENDS
WHALE ISLAND
[cawing]
[man 1] Is Gon still angling for
the Master of the Swamp?
Uh, yes.
He's been at it non-stop
for a whole week now.
[man 2] So I gotta know...
Did you really promise he could take
the Hunter Exam if he caught the thing?
[man 1]
He's a fool.
Five adults working together
couldn't real that monster in.
So what chance does
a little kid have, huh?
Sounds to me like Mito doesn't really
want him to take the Hunter Exam at all.
[man 1] Maybe so,
but wasn't Gon's old man his age
when he caught the Master of the Swamp?
[man 2 laughs]
He doesn't stand a chance.
[gasps]
Yeah!
Ah, yes!
Here he comes.
[straining]
[cries out]
[yells]
[yelling]
[crying out]
[man 1]
Look at the size of it!
That's the Master of the Swamp?
[man 2]
Wow, it's been 20 years.
[man 1] Yeah, it was Gon's dad
who caught him last time, right?
[man 2]
Like father, like son.
Gon really did it.
He actually caught the Master.
Mito, over here!
[groans]
Aunt Mito, look!
I caught him just like I said I would.
That means I can finally take
the Hunter Exam.
Right?
I'll do my best.
I'm going to be a Hunter,
just you wait and see.
[great-grandmother]
It must be in his blood.
Ging was only 12 years old
when he caught the Master
and no one has been able
to land him since.
And now his son has accomplished
the very same feat at the same age.
I don't have to tell you that his eyes
sparkle the same way as his father's.
It won't be long now
before we have to let him go.
-[Mito] Are you sure about this?
-[Gon] Yeah.
[Mito] When you were just a baby
your father abandoned you to be a Hunter.
You know that, don't you?
I do.
He chose being a Hunter
over his own son.
-[Gon] Yeah, isn't that amazing?
-[Mito] Huh?
It must be an awesome job
if it was worth leaving his kid.
Don't you think?
But being a Hunter is a dangerous job.
You could die at any time
for any number of ridiculous reasons.
-[Mito] Don't you understand?
-[Gon sighs]
No, I don't.
But I want to understand.
I want to find out why it was so important
to my dad.
That's why I've got to do it.
[sighs]
Just as I thought.
You're just like Ging.
I promise you. I'll pass the exam.
The next time you see me
I will be a Hunter.
Instead, promise you'll come home safe.
Think you can do that for me?
Yep, I sure can.
[both]
Pinky swear, so if I lie
stick a thousand needles
in my eye.
And seal it with a...
-[Mito] kiss.
-[Gon] kiss...
[Gon draws out the word]
[laughs]
Huh?
[Gon cries out]
Gon.
Aunt Mito, thank you.
[seagull cawing]
[everyone] Goodbye!
[man] Good luck, Gon!
Get out there and knock 'em dead,
do you hear me?
We believe in you, buddy.
Thanks, everybody. I'm going to be
the best Hunter in the world.
And as soon as I make that happen,
I'll be back.
I'll see you all again!
[man laughs]
The best Hunter in the world, huh?
The kid thinks this will be easy.
[man 2]
Every single year,
millions of the world's
most skilled applicants
apply for the Hunter Exam.
But only a handful make the cut.
Be careful about saying stuff
you can't back up, kid.
[men laugh]
[man 1]
What are you doing, Katzo?
[man 2]
With the way things are going for you,
you're never going to make it as a sailor.
-[laughter]
-[Katzo yelps]
[laughter]
What's wrong?
Why are you bent over like that?
[captain]
Hey, slackers.
Get back to work!
[men]
Aye, aye, sir.
[Katzo groans]
You!
Got wax in your ears?
Get moving!
Aye, aye, sir. Right away
[Gon] Wait!
[gasps]
Thanks a lot.
There's a storm coming.
[captain] Huh?
And how exactly do you know that?
Sea cranes.
That's what all of them are saying.
What?
Also...
[inhales deeply]
There's a really big one
heading right for us.
-[groans]
-[Gon] It's true.
I can tell by the way it smells.
[captain] This boy...
Those eyes.
Could he be...
[thunder clapping]
[ocean rumbling loudly]
[everyone screaming]
Captain!
The mast won't hold out for much longer.
We should lower the sails.
Don't be stupid.
We can't quit when the fun is
just about to start.
[chuckles]
Here we go!
Now, take her hard to port.
[yelling] Let's fly!
HUNTER GLOSSARY
GON
[men groaning]
Ahh! I've faced bigger waves than that
and lived.
Hey, take over the helm.
Aye, aye, sir.
[gagging]
Damned if this ain't the most
worthless crew I've seen in years.
[men groaning]
Not a one of them has got
his sea legs. Pathetic.
And they think they can pass
the Hunter Exam?
They're good for a laugh,
that's for sure.
-[Gon] Here, try these herbs.
-Hm?
Chew them up real good
and you'll feel better.
[struggling to speak]
Water...
[Gon] Sit tight, it's on its way.
Huh, that boy again.
[crunching]
[captain] Hm.
[crackling, chewing]
[groaning]
That's what I call a sour apple.
[captain] Huh, I see.
Seems there's a few
with some iron in them, after all.
-Coming through.
-[captain grumbles]
Here, I got you water.
Thank you.
[Gon] There, drink up.
[gulping water]
[Katzo sighs]
[grumbles]
[chuckles]
Hm.
Hm?
You're the best.
Thanks for your help, Mr. Katzo.
[ocean rumbling loudly]
[captain] Right, then. Go down the line
and tell me all your names.
My name's Gon.
I am called Kurapika.
The name is Leorio.
Good, good. Now why do you boys want
to become Hunters?
Whoa! You're not an examiner,
so what's with the third degree?
Just answer the question, dummy.
I will. Because my dad is a Hunter.
Hm?
[Gon] Being a hunter was the most
important thing in the world to my dad.
And I want to know why.
That's why I left Whale Island.
Whale Island?
So it is him.
This is Ging's son.
It looks like the day has come at last.
[Leorio] Hey, kid.
You don't have to tell
that old guy nothin'.
But he asked why I'm here.
It's not a secret.
Look, get with the program.
It's us versus him.
And I'm not telling him
why I'm here.
[Kurapika] I'm afraid I agree with Leorio.
Huh?
That's Mr. Leorio to you, you brat.
Show a little respect for your elders.
But why not dodge the question
by simply offering the man
a plausible lie?
Hey! Are you even listening to me?
However, it is quite shameful
to rely upon deceit.
As for me,
I cannot reveal my reasons here.
I have my share of secrets.
Deep secrets, which I do not intend
to expose at this time.
That is why
I will not answer your question.
Hey, I was talking to you, punk.
[captain] So, both of you flat out refuse
to answer my question.
Hey, Katzo.
Yes, what is it, Captain?
Get a hold of the Exam Committee for me.
Let them know we've got two more dropouts.
[both gasp]
Wait, what do you mean?
Still haven't figured it out, huh?
You see,
the Hunter Exam has already started.
[both] It has?
[captain] There are as many
Hunter wannabes in this world
as there are stars in the sky.
And the examiners, well...
The fact is, they don't have the time
nor the resources to go through them all.
That's where people like me come in
to pick up the slack.
Screen all of the applicants
and trim the fat.
I've already notified the committee
about the rest of the lot.
Not a one of them made the cut.
-[Leorio] What?
-[Kurapika] Huh?
[captain] That was just a little storm
and look how they handled it.
They'd never survive
the later stages of the exam.
In other words,
the only way you three are moving on
to the next portion of the Exam
is if I give you the go-ahead.
So, I'll ask you again.
And think carefully before you answer.
You catch all that?
Hm?
[Leorio]
You could have told us that sooner.
I am the sole survivor
of the Kurta Clan.
Four years ago,
my entire clan was annihilated
by a band of criminals.
That is why I want to become a Hunter.
To capture the Phantom Troupe.
Sounds like you want to be
a Black List Hunter.
And the Phantom Troupe is
a Class-A bounty.
Even the most seasoned Hunters
can't touch them.
You know it's a suicide mission, right?
Death is not among my fears.
But there is one thing I do fear,
and one thing alone.
That time will quiet the rage in my heart.
So, in other words,
you're out for revenge.
But you don't really need to become
a Hunter
just so you can settle an old score,
do you?
That is the stupidest question
I have ever heard, Leorio.
That's "Mr. Leorio."
There are places only Hunters can go,
intel only they can access,
and actions only they can take.
There are more reasons
but those are the only three
that you have a chance of comprehending.
-[screaming]
-[Gon] Hey!
Why do you want to become a Hunter,
Mr. Leorio?
Who, me?
Well, it's pretty simple, really.
-For the money.
-Huh?
[loudly] Money can buy everything
you've ever wanted.
A big mansion.
A cool car.
And top-shelf booze.
[chuckles]
If only you could buy class as well,
Leorio.
That was strike three.
Step outside.
Time to finish off the
filthy Kurta bloodline once and for all.
Take that back, Leorio!
I said, take it back.
It's "Mr. Leorio."
[captain]
Hey, where do you boys think you're going?
I'm not finished with you yet.
[Gon] Let them go.
They're fine.
It's like Aunt Mito told me once,
You can never understand a person unless
you can understand what makes them angry.
It's how you get to know someone.
So whatever they're feeling so upset about
is really important to them.
It's up to them now.
Nothing we can do but stay out of the way.
[crewman] Captain!
Look. Over there.
[grunts]
[thunder claps]
If we get caught up in that waterspout,
the ship is going to sink for sure.
Get the sails lowered. Now!
-Right.
-Anything I can do?
Yeah, follow me up on deck.
-Go with them. I'll take the helm.
-Aye!
All right, then, hard to starboard.
[sailor] Move it!
If we get caught in the waterspout
we're done for!
-[men clamoring]
-[ship creaking]
[Gon straining]
Take back what you said about my clan.
I will forgive you if you repent, Leorio.
You owe me an apology.
And I'm not telling you again.
I'm not repenting for anything,
hear me?
[softly] Very well.
[men crying out]
[Gon] Mr. Katzo!
[grunts]
[groaning]
[both] Damn!
Come on, let's get them back on deck!
[straining]
[Leorio] You idiot!
If it hadn't been for us,
you'd be shark bait.
You owe me big time, kid.
And don't you forget it.
Honestly, how reckless can you be?
But it's fine, you caught me.
-Huh?
You both did.
You both caught me together.
I guess you might have a point.
[Katzo] Gon!
[Gon] Hey, Mr. Katzo.
Thanks, Gon, you're incredible.
You saved my life back there.
Yeah, well, I didn't do it all alone.
Those two over there
helped rescue you, too.
[Katzo]
He's right. Thank you both.
Please. No thanks necessary.
Yeah, no prob.
We're just glad to see
you made it okay.
Me too.
In fact, I ought to get back to my post
right away.
[Leorio chuckles]
Hm?
[Kurapika chuckles]
What's so funny?
I'm embarrassed at my behavior.
Pardon my rudeness, Mr. Leorio.
I wasn't expecting that.
Just forget it.
You can drop the Mister.
Leorio is fine.
I'm sorry, too.
And I take back everything
that I said to you before.
That was wrong of me.
[Kurapika] No, it's fine.
[captain laughs]
You three are growing on me.
So...
I'll make sure all three of you
get safely dropped off
at the port closest to the Exam site.
How does that sound? [chuckles]
You will?
[Kurapika]
But, what about your test?
It's like I said, I decide who goes on
to take the Exam.
Congratulations!
You're all moving on.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
[loudly] All right! [chuckles]
[narrator]
And so, Gon finally began his journey
to do what his father did
before him.
To become a Hunter.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time:
"Test x of x Tests."
Don't miss it!